http://www.aclam.org/privacy-policy

Home
Members Only
Privacy Policy
Home ACLAMPrivacy Policy
What information do we collect?We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order or fill out a form. When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number or credit card information. You may, however, visit the ACLAM Home web site anonymously.What do we use your information for?Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following waysTo personalize your experience (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)To improve our website (we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)To improve customer service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)To process your transactions To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site featureACLAM may share your ACLAM membership information, from which a member may opt out.
To send periodic emails (The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.) Note: you have the option to unsubscribe from receiving future emails.To confirm your certification status if requested by a third party.How do we protect your information?We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information. We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via the current version of Transport Security Layer technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.  After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.Do we use cookies?Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart, keep track of advertisements and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. If you prefer, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies via your browser settings. Like most websites, if you turn your cookies off, some of our services may not function properly. However, you can still place orders by contacting customer service.Do we disclose any information to outside parties?ACLAM may share your ACLAM membership information, from which a member may opt out. We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your other personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.Online Privacy Policy OnlyThis online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.Terms and ConditionsPlease also visit our Disclaimer and Copyright sections establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website.Your ConsentBy using our site, you consent to our websites privacy policy.Changes to our Privacy PolicyIf we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, send an email notifying you of any changes, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.This policy was last modified on 5/3/18.Contacting UsIf there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.ACLAMDr. Melvin W. Balk96 Chester StreetChester, NH 03036Phone: 603-887-2467Fax: 603-887-0096Email: mwbaclam@gsinet.netACLAM General Data Protection Regulation PolicyThis ACLAM General Data Protection Regulation Policy (''Policy") sets forth ACLAM’s Policy with respect to the Processing Personal Data as part of performing under those agreements that deal with Personal Data for which GRPR Regulations (the "Data Protection Law") are applicable. This Policy is effective as of the Implantation Date of the Regulations. This Policy consists of:SECTION 1: PurposeThis Policy relates to ACLAM’s Processing of Personal Data and compliance with Data Protection Law (as defined herein).SECTION 2: Definitions"Data Protection Law" means any law, rule, regulation, decree, statute, or other enactment, order, mandate or resolution, applicable to ACLAM and its Customers, relating to data security, data protection and/or privacy, including Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to processing of personal data and the free movement of that data ("GDPR"), and any implementing, derivative or related legislation, rule, regulation, and regulatory guidance, as amended, extended, repealed and replaced, or re-enacted."Personal Data" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ("Data Subject"). An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by referencing an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier, or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural, or social identity of that natural person."Personal Data Breach" means a breach of security leading to the accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure of, or access to Personal Data, whether transmitted, stored, or otherwise Processed."Processing" means any operation or set of operations that is performed on Personal Data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure, or destruction. "Process" and "Processed" will have a corresponding meaning.SECTION 3: GDPR Requirements(1) With respect to any Agreement for which the Data Protection Law is applicable, ACLAM in its capacity as a Data Processor or sub processor of Personal Data under an Agreement with Customer, agrees to the following:Process Personal Data with Agreements from Customer, including with regard to transfers of Personal Data to a third country or an international organization, unless required to do so by European Union or Member State law to which ACLAM is subject. In the event of such transfer ACLAM will inform Customer of that legal requirement before processing, unless that law prohibits such information on important grounds of public interest,(i) ensure that persons authorized to Process the Personal Data have committed themselves to confidentiality or are under an appropriate statutory obligation of confidentiality,(ii) take all measures required in accordance with good industry practice and by Data Protection Law relating to data security (including pursuant to Article 32 of the GDPR),(iii) not-engage another party to Process Personal Data without prior written disclosure by ACLAM,(iv) taking into account the nature of the Processing, assist Customer by appropriate technical and organizational measures, insofar as this is possible, for the fulfillment of ACLAM’s and Customer’s obligation to respond to requests for exercising the Data Subject's rights laid down in Data Protection Law (including Chapter Ill of the GDPR),(v) with respect to any Agreement, ACLAM will assist Customer in ensuring compliance with data security, Personal Data Breach, data protection impact assessments, and engaging in other consultations, pursuant to Data Protection Law,(vi) at the choice of Customer, promptly delete or return all the Personal Data to Customer after the end of the provision of Services under any Agreement relating to Processing, and delete existing copies unless European Union or Member State law requires storage of Personal Data,(vii) comply with all audit requirements of the Data Protection Law to demonstrate compliance with Data Protection Law (including the obligations laid down in Article 28 of the GDPR) and allow for and contribute to audits, including inspections, conducted by Customer or another auditor if mandated by the Data Protection Law, and(viii) inform Customer, in ACLAM’s opinion, that an instruction infringes Data Protection Law.(2) The subject matter of the Processing, including the Processing operations carried out by ACLAM on behalf of Customer and Customer's Processing instructions for ACLAM, may be described in statement of work, Customer purchase order or a written agreement signed by the parties' authorized representatives.(3) ACLAM will notify Customer without undue delay upon becoming aware of a Personal Data Breach.(4) Where in ACLAM’s opinion Customer faces an actual or potential claim arising out of or related to violation of any Data Protection Law (e.g., Article 82 of the GDPR) concerning ACLAM’s Services, ACLAM will assist in providing all materials and information requested by Customer that is relevant to the defense of such claim and the underlying circumstances concerning the claim.Please direct inquires toACLAM Dr. Melvin W. Balk 96 Chester Street Chester, NH 03036 Phone: 603-887-2467 Fax: 603-887-0096 Email: mwbaclam@gsinet.net
